<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Devices | Jairo Narro</title>
    <link>https://jaironarro.github.io/website/tag/medical-devices/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jaironarro.github.io/website/tag/medical-devices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Medical Devices</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jaironarro.github.io/website/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Medical Devices</title>
      <link>https://jaironarro.github.io/website/tag/medical-devices/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRISPR-based Microfluidic Biosensor</title>
      <link>https://jaironarro.github.io/website/project/crispr-based-microfluidic-biosensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaironarro.github.io/website/project/crispr-based-microfluidic-biosensor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the Cleveland Clinic - UTEC Challenge 2022, we proposed the design of a  microfluidic sensor that integrates the CRISPR/Cas13 system for the diagnosis of infectious diseases. The microfluidic device consists of three modules: RNA extraction (1), RNA elution (2) and CRISPR reaction (3). If the pathogen is present, the cas13 collateral cleavage function will be activated, and the reporters will release a fluorescent signal that can be measured with a mobile app. This low-cost and easy-to-handle diagnostic platform can be implemented in remote areas with medical centers that do not have adequate infrastructure or equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joystick-operated computer mouse</title>
      <link>https://jaironarro.github.io/website/project/cwru/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jaironarro.github.io/website/project/cwru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We do a lot of needful activities with computers. Unfortunately, not everyone can use a computer. Due to accidents, infections, or diseases, people can suffer the amputation of both upper limbs. Therefore, we designed aUto_JD, a joystick-operated computer mouse that will allow people with bilateral upper extremity amputations to use a computer properly. With aUtoJD, we hope believe computer interactions such as surfing the Internet, playing video games, typing documents, chatting with friends, and many more activities are highly achievable for people with amputations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
